BILL ALBIN: Hello, I'm Bill Albin.
In this clip, we're going to talk about a tripod.
Tripods are very important to every reporter or a photographer's work.
The tripod is where you put your camera, obviously, but it's more than that.
This is what you exactly what you need to make sure every shot is better.
When you're shooting video, it's important to have a steady, clear shot.
And no matter how steady your hands are, they will never be as steady as a stationary tripod.
So when you're using a tripod, there's a few things you need to know.
For example, the tripod should always be eye level to the talent.
And what that means is the person on camera, the camera itself should be looking right at them.
So you'd always want to bring your tripod to the eye level, or the camera really, to the eye level of the talent.
And what that means is, where the camera sits should be looking me right in the eye.
So then you set up your tripod.
Then what you do is you have a little bubble there, much like any construction worker or anyone who needs something perfectly level or carpenter and so forth.
You would make sure that your tripod is exactly level.
That way, I don't end up looking like I'm tilted or something while I'm on the news.
Once you have your tripod set up, make sure that it's on a proper position.
Make sure that none of the legs are down a hill or that none of the--you're on something that will cause damage or problems with the camera.